MADELEINE MILASAS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & PASSIONATE TECHNOLOGIST

PROFILE

Hi I'm Maddi, a software engineer from Sydney. I enthusiastically unpack problems and I love to use data to develop beautiful & compelling customer experiences that provide real value. I'm passionate about always learning & creating with code - with a background in film/TV/events technology and interaction design, I adore collaboration, innovation and harnessing the power of combining creative thinking with technical skill.

SKILLS



















FRONT-END TECHNOLOGIES:

JavaScript (ES6), React, Redux, GraphQL, Flow, TypeScript, ReasonML HTML5, CSS3, Testing frameworks such as Jest, Testing Library, WDIO

BACK-END TECHNOLOGIES:

.NET, Node, Ruby on Rails, Haskell, AWS, Serverless

FURTHER TOOLS:

New Relic, Sumo Logic, LaunchDarkly, Segment, Amplitude, FullStory Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket including Bitbucket Pipelines, OpsGenie

I'M AT HOME IN:

Agile cross-functional teams, Lean software development, Service-oriented architectures, Event driven architecture

PORTFOLIO + CONTACT



+61 421 644 469

maddi.milasas@gmail.com

Dual AUS / EU Citizenship

in/madeleine-milasas

github.com/madeleinemila

EDUCATION

Web Development Immersive

General Assembly, 2018

Grad. Diploma of Interaction Design & Electronic Arts

University of Sydney, 2014 Y High Distinction Average

Bachelor of Arts

University of Sydney, 2008

EXPERIENCE

Developer Apr 2018 - Oct 2020

Ansarada

Front and back-end development (React & .NET) for virtual data room provider Ansarada.

Collaborating in cross-functional agile teams, I built and maintained full-stack features in a microservices architecture and designed implementation plans. I loved wiring up integrations to analytics tools to better understand our customers and I eagerly participated in customer research alongside designers and product managers.

I specialised in front-end development, creating experiences with React & Redux, and I was a contributor to Ansarada's design system to ensure a consistent UI experience across the platform. I was responsible for my own testing and deployment, which cultivated skills in writing modular, maintainable, testable code, writing tests at all levels of the test pyramid, and in debugging CI/CD processes. I was also responsible for uncovering performance issues and responding to alerts and incidents.

- · Delivered features for cloud document management, client success administration, activity feeds, licensing and customer identity, all in a domain that requires high security.
- 3 x winner of company-wide hackathons (3 out of 3 entries).
- Saved more than 1 developer/mth time and saved expenses with vendors via innovations in engineering processes.
- Performed scrum master and feature lead roles, including designing & leading full-stack solutions.
- Independently coordinated study groups and workshops on subjects such as React and Functional Programming.
- Open source contributor.
- Mentored aspiring developers through coordinating General Assembly office visits, public speaking, and mentoring GA students outside the office. Contributed to our wider dev community as a videographer for developer conferences.
- Member of Ansarada's diversity & inclusion committee.

EXPERIENCE (CONT.)

Master Control Operator, Media Operator

Deluxe MediaCloud (SBS Television)

2015 - 2018

Video, audio & communication signal control & manipulation for Special Broadcasting Service (SBS). Highlights include:

- Successful high-profile, high-pressure broadcasts such as Eurovision Song Contest, Tour de France, UEFA Champions League, Australian & **US** elections
- Trained & mentored new employees
- · Collaborated on the transition from proprietary hardware to cloudbased solutions

Lighting Technician

Production Resource Group (USA)

2015

Concert tour & festival lighting rig building and programming, including programming 3D projection mapping.

Media Operator, Media Manager, Studio Technical Director

SBS Television 2012 - 2015

Twice awarded company-wide excellence (GEM) award

Interaction Designer

The Digital Shamans Contract-based, 2013 & 2014

Design, programming & implementation of interactive multimedia installations.

• Installation 'Dichroic Dimensions' exhibited at Vivid Sydney 2014, Museum of Contemporary Art facade

Film/TV Data Wrangler Film/TV/Events Production Coordinator

Freelance 2010 - 2012

Visual Effects Artist

The Lab Sydney 2008 - 2010

Feature film & TV visual effects for titles such as 'Tomorrow When The War Began' and Baz Luhrmann's 'Australia'

3 x AACTA Award Winner for Best Visual Effects

REFERENCES

References available on request